Esta lição 29 de Pimsleur Inglês 1.
Listen. Hi Nancy, how are you?
Fine thanks, and you? Not bad.
Now ask what that means.
What does that mean?
O que quer dizer not bad?
What does not bad mean? Answer: Not bad.
可以指出， nada
mau.
Not bad means nada mau.
Not bad means nada
mau.
Say that you understand now.
I understand now.
E como se diz alguém que você não entende?
I don't understand.
I'm sorry, I don't understand.
Say again. Nada mal.
Not bad.
Now say,
nós estamos aqui.
We're here. Por alguns
For a few days.
Diga que vocês estão aqui por alguns dias.
We are here for a few days.
Ask how long.
How long?
Agora pergunte-lhe quanto tempo ela vai ficar.
How long are you going to stay?
Stay. How long
are you going to stay?
Answer. Nós vamos ficar.
We are going to stay.
Por alguns dias.
For a few days.
Então nós vamos embora.
Then we're leaving.
Nós vamos para Boston.
We're going to Boston.
Juntos. Together.
Nós não temos muito tempo.
We don't have much time.
Eu tenho 200 dólares.
I have 200 dollars.
Mas eu não preciso de nada.
But I don't need anything.
Meu marido não precisa de nada.
My husband doesn't need anything.
E nós não temos muito tempo.
And we don't have much time.
Nós vamos ficar.
We're going to stay.
For a few days.
Listen, a few weeks. Ask what that means.
What does that mean?
Ask, o que quer dizer a few weeks?
What does a few weeks mean?
Weeks. A few weeks
means algumas semanas. Say in English,
algumas semanas.
A few weeks.
Weeks. Agora,
usando o número, tente dizer uma semana.
One week. Week.
One week. Quanto tempo?
How long? For how long?
Uma semana. One week.
One week. Nós vamos
We're going to stay.
Por uma semana.
For one week.
We're going to stay for one week.
Juntos. Together.
Então nós vamos embora.
And then we're leaving.
Quanto tempo faz que vocês estão aqui?
Listen. How long have you been here? Now listen and repeat.
How long have you been here?
Been. Been. Have been.
Have you been?
How long?
How long have you been here?
Note que você usou a palavra have novamente. Esta palavra
se usa com been para indicar que alguém tem estado num lugar durante algum tempo
e continua neste lugar. Pergunte outra vez: Quanto tempo faz
que vocês estão aqui?
How long have you been here?
How long
have you been here?
Usando for, tente dizer faz algumas semanas.
For a few weeks.
For.
Pergunte-lhe outra vez quanto tempo faz que ela está aqui.
How long have you been here?
Você quer dizer, eu estou aqui faz algumas semanas.
Try to answer. Eu estou aqui.
I have been here.
I've been here.
I've. I've been here for
a few weeks.
Você notou a contração? Você vai utilizar a contração de
I have nesse contexto. Agora diga: eu
estou aqui faz algumas semanas.
I've been here for a few weeks.
I've been here.
Agora tente perguntar quanto tempo faz que ela está em Boston.
How long have you been in Boston?
Desde ontem, primeiro ontem. Listen and repeat.
Yesterday. Day.
Er.
Yesterday.
Yesterday. Say the word
onting.
Yesterday.
但是 onting.
Listen and repeat. Since yesterday.
Since.
Since. Since yesterday.
Say again. Desde ontem.
Since yesterday.
Try to say: nós estamos aqui desde ontem.
Use a contração de we have.
We've been here since yesterday.
We've, we've.
We've been here. We've been here
since yesterday.
O que você comprou ontem? Listen. What did
you buy yesterday? Agora escute e repita a primeira parte.
What did you buy?
Buy. Buy. Did.
Did.
Did buy.
Did you buy? What did
you buy? Note a
palavra did. Esta palavra interrogativa se usa para indicar
algo que alguém fez no passado. Note também como as palavras no
meio daquela pergunta se juntam. Pergunte novamente: O que
você comprou? What did
you buy? What did you
buy?
Now try to ask. O que você comprou ontem?
What did you buy yesterday?
Ela diz, eu comprei algo. Listen and repeat.
I bought something.
Bought. Bought. I bought.
Pergunte o que ela comprou.
What did you buy?
Ask. O que você comprou ontem?
What did you buy yesterday?
Try to ask. O que você fez ontem?
What did you do yesterday?
Do. Did you
do? What did
you do yesterday?
Now ask: Quanto tempo faz que você está aqui?
How long have you been here?
Desde ontem.
Since yesterday.
Ask: O que você fez ontem?
What did you do yesterday?
Answer: Eu comprei algo.
I bought something.
Ask, o que você comprou?
What did you buy?
Answer, eu comprei um vinho.
I bought some wine.
Some wine. E eu comprei
um jornal. Listen. And I bought a newspaper.
Ask what that means.
What does that mean?
O que quer dizer a palavra newspaper?
What does the word newspaper mean?
What does that word mean?
Newspaper means jornal. Jornal.
Listen and repeat. Newspaper.
Paper. Paper.
News. Newspaper.
Newspaper. Say again.
Jornal.
Newspaper. A newspaper.
Diga que você comprou
um jornal. I bought
a newspaper.
I bought a newspaper.
Um jornal americano.
An American newspaper.
Now ask me how I am.
How are you? Answer: Nada
mal. Not bad.
Not bad. Now ask:
Quanto tempo faz que você está aqui?
How long have you been here?
How long
Answer: Desde ontem.
Since yesterday. Eu estou
aqui desde ontem.
I've been here since yesterday.
O que você fez ontem?
What did you do yesterday?
Sei. Eu comprei um vinho.
I bought some wine.
E um jornal americano.
And an American newspaper.
I bought some wine and an American newspaper.
Say, meu marido não tem vinho.
My husband doesn't have any wine.
Sé, eu comprei um vinho.
I bought some wine.
Para meu marido.
For my husband.
The newspaper
is for me.
For me.
Listen and repeat. And the wine
is for him.
Him.
Him. For him. The wine is
for him. How do
you say para ele?
For him. Say again.
O vinho é para ele.
The wine is for him.
The wine is
Eu comprei café também. Use some.
I bought some coffee too.
O café é para minha amiga Mary.
The coffee is for my friend Mary.
O café é para ela. Listen and repeat.
The coffee is for her.
Her. Her.
For her.
The coffee is
Say,
it's for
her.
For her.
It's for her.
Say, the wine is for him.
For him. Say,
"E o café é para ela." And
the coffee is for her.
For her.
É assim que se pergunta: Você gosta de vinho?
Listen and repeat. Do you like wine?
Like. You like.
Do you like? Do you
like wine?
Ask again. Você gosta de vinho?
Do you like wine?
Now try to say eu gosto.
I like. I like.
Eu gosto de vinho.
I like wine.
Yes, I like wine.
Now say, "Eu gostaria de um pouco de vinho." I'd
like some wine.
I'd like some wine.
Ask, "Você gostaria de um pouco de vinho?" Would
you like some wine?
Would you like some wine?
Answer: Não, obrigada.
No thanks. Por que não?
Why not? Why not?
Say, eu não quero nada.
I don't want anything.
Mas o meu marido gostaria de uma cerveja.
But my husband would like a beer.
Eu acho que ele gostaria de uma cerveja.
I think he would like a beer.
Say, aqui está uma cerveja.
Here's a beer.
É para ele.
It's for him. It's for him.
How do you say? É para ela.
It's for her.
Ask. Você gosta de cerveja?
Do you like beer?
Try to answer. Não é nada mau.
It's not bad.
Agora imagine que você chegou ontem a Boston.
Você gosta muito da cidade e pensa em ficar uma semana.
Você está falando com Mrs. Johnson, a quem acabam de te apresentar.
Answer her questions. Responda as perguntas dela.
I'm pleased to meet you, Mr. Martins. How long have you
Since yesterday.
I've been here since yesterday.
What did you do yesterday? Diga-lhe que você comprou algo
para sua esposa.
I bought something for my wife.
Say, eu comprei algo para ela.
I bought something for her.
How long are you going to stay in Boston?
One week.
I'm going to stay for
one week.
Tiga Lee, eu gostaria de ficar algumas semanas.
Literalmente. Por algumas semanas.
I'd like to stay for a few weeks.
Mas eu não tenho muito tempo.
But I don't have much time.
Do you like Boston?
Yes, I do.
I like Boston very much.
Nesta lição de inglês um se incluem exercícios de leitura.